# Satyam sinha

Contact: 8158914106 GitHub: satyamsinha111

Email: satyamsinha8158@gmail.com

**Location:** Rishra (Hoogly) **Experience**: 2+ yrs



#### **ABOUT ME**

A software professional dedicated towards my job and have a target to learn as much as possible and stay updated with the latest technology trends. I carry a 2 plus year experience in javascript on building frontend sides of the application and some backend part also. My expections are to learn more about technology like React, Angular, Nodejs backend and database stuffs also.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 1. COLORBRACKET TECHNOLOGY LLP (2021-2022)

I worked here as a Javascript developer.

Products I worked on:

Name of the project - Zapster Admin Panel

**Duration of the project -**

26 December 2020 to 30 April 2021

#### My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline
- Debugging and writing unit test cases for the project using karma and jasmine
- Communicate with backend for the apis.
- Writing testable and maintainable code.
- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push development code.

## Technology used -

Angular, Google maps, AppSync(AWS service), Serverless Node js (For backend programming), Maria DB (As database), Flutter (For android app)

Team size: 3 people

Name of the project - Zapster Partner App

**Duration of the project -**

1 May 2021 to 15 July 2021

My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline

Debugging and writing unit test cases for the project using karma and jasmine

- Communicate with backend for the apis.

- Writing testable and maintainable code.

- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push

development code.

Technology used -

Angular, Google maps, AppSync(AWS service), FCM, Serverless Node js (For backend

programming), Maria DB (As database), Flutter (For android app)

**Team size:** 3 people

Name of the project - Echoltech (TK03 Module)

**Duration of the project -**

1st of August 2021 to 30th of September 2021

My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline

- Debugging and writing unit test cases for the project using karma and jasmine

- Communicate with backend for the apis.

- Writing testable and maintainable code.

- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push

development code.

Technology used -

Angular ,ASP .Net (For backend programming), SQL server (As database), Docker

Team size: 2 people

Name of the project: URA Private Web (Canned Application)

**Duration:** 

1st of October 2021 to 30<sup>th</sup> of October 2021

My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline

- Communicate with backend for the apis.

- Writing testable and maintainable code.

- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push

development code.

Technology used -

Angular Node js (For backend programming), JSON (As database), Ngnix as web proxy

Team size - 1

Name of the project: JSON UI Builder

**Duration:** 

1st of November 2021 to 10<sup>th</sup> of November 2021

My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline

- Writing testable and maintainable code.

- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push

development code.

Technology used -

Vanilla Javascript

Team size - 1

Name of the project: Mantro (ERP Restaurent Application)

#### **Duration:**

1st of December 2021 to 10<sup>th</sup> of January 2022

### My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline
- Writing testable and maintainable code.
- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push development code.

## Technology used -

Angular, Google maps , AppSync(AWS service), FCM ,Serverless Node js (For backend programming), Maria DB (As database), ionic (For android app) ,

Rxjs(State management)

Team size - 2

#### 2. NAVIGATORS SOFTWARES PVT. LTD. (2022-Present)

I am working here as a software developer.

Product I am working on is responsible for insurance and policy related stuff based on Barbados Client.

Name of the project: Consumer Guarantee Insurance (CGI)

## **Duration:**

1st of March 2022 to till date.

## My Responsibility to the project -

- Taking care of the task to be completed before deadline
- Writing testable and maintainable code.
- Taking responsibility that Production should go smoothly without any latency and delay.
- Ensuring a stable production system. I.e nothing breaks in the server while we push development code.

- Leading a team of frontend developers.
- Taking care of the delivery of the sprint without delay.
- Analysing if there is any bottleneck in completing the task and way to fix that.

### Technology used -

Angular, S3 AWS, Jenkins, Docker, ASP. Net (For backend programming), SQL server (As database), Angular material

Team size - 10

#### **EDUCATION**

1. SAINT THOMAS HIGH SCHOOL (- 2013)

Passed Madhyamik with 7.4 CGPA

2. SAINT JOSEPH HIGH SCHOOL (2013-2015)

Passed higher secondary with 58%

3. BC COLLEGE (2015-2018)

Dropped math honours in last year.

4. ABS Academy (2019-2022)

BCA – 9.0 CGPA

## **SKILLSET**

- Angular Javascript Typescript Node js MongoDB SQL